Register of the George Sokolsky Papers, 1916-1962
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1916-1962
  - Weisfeldt, M. J., 1943 (Folder 3)
  - Welch, Rachel
    - 1954-1955 (Folder 4)
    - 1956-1959 (Folder 5)
  - The Welch Daily News, 1943-1949 (Folder 6)
  - Wellington, Martha, 1948-1961 (Folder 7)
  - Wells, John F., 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Wen, Shih-tsen
    - 1920-1921 (Folder 9)
    - 1922 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - 1923 (Folder 2)
    - 1924-1925 (Folder 3)
    - 1926-1937 (Folder 4)
  - Wen, Tsung Yao, 1920-1923 (Folder 5)
  - Werner, Morris R., 1919-1927 (Folder 6)
  - West, Paul B., 1939 (Folder 7)
  - Wetmore, Rae, 1960-1961 (Folder 8)
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, 1961 (Folder 9)
  - Whalen, Grover A., 1947-1953 (Folder 10)
  - Wheeler, Burton K., 1931-1962 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Wheeler, Robert, 1960-1961 (Folder 2)
  - Wheeler, William J., 1947-1949 (Folder 3)
  - Wheelock, Ward, 1951-1953 (Folder 4)
  - White, Elizabeth, 1950 (Folder 5)
  - White, William A., 1936-1943 (Folder 6)
  - Whitin, E. Stagg, 1917-1942 (Folder 7)
  - Whitmore, Virginia, 1944-1951 (Folder 8)
  - Whitney, Courtney, 1951-1958 (Folder 9)
  - Who's Who In America, 1941-1960 (Folder 10)
  - Whyte, Frederick, Sir, 1931-1933 (Folder 11)
  - The Wichita Beacon, 1939-1960 (Folder 12)
  - Wick, James L., 1944-1951 (Folder 13)
  - Wickersham, Cornelius, 1961-1962 (Folder 14)
  - Wieck, Fred, 1951 (Folder 15)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1943-1949 (Folder 16)
  - Wiley, Alexander, 1951-1952 (Folder 17)
  - Wiley, Harvey W., 1960 (Folder 18)
  - William, Maurice, 1931-1934 (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - Williams, Roy, 1937-1938 (Folder 2)
  - Williams, Walter, 1932-1934 (Folder 3)
  - Williams, Whiting, 1950 (Folder 4)
  - Williamson, Betty, 1950 (Folder 5)
  - Williamson, Robert D., 1940 (Folder 6)
  - Willkie, Philip, 1940 (Folder 7)
  - Willkie, Wendell, Mr. and Mrs., 1940 (Folder 8)
  - Willoughby, Charles A., 1950-1962 (Folder 9)
  - Wilson, Charles E., 1950 (Folder 10)
  - Wilson, Kendrick, 1961 (Folder 11)
  - Winchell, Walter, 1953-1954 (Folder 12)
  - Winogrand, Maurice, 1944-1953 (Folder 13)
  - Wise, Jonah B., 1934-1959 (Folder 14)
  - Wise, Stephen S., 1935-1945 (Folder 15)
  - Witherspoon, Maurice M., 1946-1950 (Folder 16)
  - Withington, Mildred, 1932-1934 (Folder 17)
  - Withington, Ruth, 1934-1935 (Folder 18)
  - Wittmer, Felix, 1951 (Folder 19)
  - Wolman, Leo, 1935-1949 (Folder 20)
  - Wood, Charles W., 1950 (Folder 21)
  - Wood, F. R., 1950-1951 (Folder 22)
  - Wood, Robert E., 1942-1952 (Folder 23)
  - Woodford, Jack, 1949-1951 (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - Woodhead, H. G. W., 1924-1930 (Folder 2)
  - Workman, Robert D., 1944-1950 (Folder 3)
  - Worrilow, William H., Jr., 1960 (Folder 4)
  - Wren, Jack, 1952-1953 (Folder 5)
  - Wright, Cobina, 1953-1954 (Folder 6)
  - Wright, Quincy, 1930-1934 (Folder 7)
  - Wu, Chao-chu, 1919-1934 (Folder 8)
  - Wyman, Louis C., 1956 (Folder 9)
  - Yankwich, Leon, 1948-1954 (Folder 10)
  - Yorty, Sam, 1955 (Folder 11)
  - Yost, Thomas M., 1961 (Folder 12)
  - Young, Arthur, 1930-1931 (Folder 13)
  - Young, Stephen M., 1962 (Folder 14)
  - Young Americans for Freedom, 1960-1962 (Folder 15)
  - Zeckendorf, William, Jr., 1959 (Folder 16)
  - Zehner, J. Alexander, 1950-1954 (Folder 17)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1920-1962
  - Address, n.d. Typescript (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - "Amah Pan on Velocity," n.d. (pseudonym used, Georgi Gramada) Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "Amah Pan Seeks the Country," n.d. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - "Amah Pan Sees New York's Skyline," n.d. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "Amah Pan's Comment on American Women," n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "American Trade with China and Japan," n.d. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "And Then Came Ford," n.d. Typescript (Folder 7)
  - "The Anglo-Japanese Alliance," n.d. Typescript (Folder 8)
  - Article (fragment), n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - Article on American farmers, n.d. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - Article on American loan to China, n.d. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - Article on Anfu Party, Japan Advertiser, n.d. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - Article on Asheva Uskuli, n.d. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - Article on Chang Tso-lin, Japan Advertiser, n.d. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Article on Chekiang monopoly, n.d. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - Article on China Trade Act, n.d. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - Article on Chinese legal system, n.d. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - Article on conferences in Japan, n.d. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - Article on currency, n.d. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - Article on customs duties, Far Eastern Review, n.d. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - Article on foreign powers in China, Far Eastern Review, n.d. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - Article on foreign press in China, n.d. (Folder 22)
  - Article on General Kung, n.d. Typescript (Folder 23)
  - Article on Hu Han-Ming, n.d. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - Article on Jazz, n.d. Typescript (Folder 25)
  - Article on Lu Ti-ping, n.d. Typescript (Folder 26)
  - Article on mass education, n.d. Typescript (Folder 27)
  - Article on Nationalist finances, Japan Advertiser, n.d. Typescript (Folder 28)
  - Article on political appointmments, n.d. Typescript (Folder 29)
  - Article on political situation, n.d. Typescript (Folder 30)
  - Article on the press, n.d. Typescript (Folder 31)
  - Article on Russo-Asiatic Bank, North China Daily News, n.d. Typescript (Folder 32)
  - Article on Shanghai strike, n.d. Typescript (Folder 33)
  - Article on Sino-Japanese relations, n.d. Typescript (Folder 34)
  - Article on Sir Frederick Whyte, n.d. Typescript (Folder 35)
  - Article on tobacco tax, n.d. Typescript (Folder 36)
  - Article on Turkey, n.d. Typescript (Folder 37)
  - Article on Viscount Shidehara, Japan Advertiser, n.d. Typescript (Folder 38)
  - Article on Washington's Birthday ball, n.d. Typescript (Folder 39)
  - Article on wood oil, n.d. Typescript (Folder 40)
  - Articles on Chiang Kai-shek, Japan Advertiser and unknown, n.d. Two typescript texts (Folder 41)
  - Articles on the Chinese economy, n.d. Twelve typescript texts (Folder 42)
  - Articles on famine, n.d. (pseudonym used, Georgi Gramada). Two typescript texts and holograph notes (Folder 43)
  - Articles on Kuomintang Party, n.d. Two typescript texts and one holograph draft (Folder 44)
  - Articles on labor, n.d. (pseudonym used on one, Georgi Gramada). Three typescript texts (Folder 45)
  - Articles on Sun Yat-sen, n.d. (pseudonym used on one, Georgi Gramada). Five typescript texts (Folder 46)
  - "Asiatic Wives of American Husbands," n.d. Typescript (Folder 47)
  - "Bandits," Public Ledger, n.d. Typescript (Folder 48)
  - "Bandits and Politicians," n.d. Typescript (Folder 49)
  - "Birai (sic) Brith Ideals in the Far East," n.d. Two typescript copies (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - "Can There Be a Free Press in China?" n.d. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "The Chekiang Cigarette Tax: An Unwise Action," n.d. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - "Child Labour Commission," n.d. Typescript text in two parts (Folder 4)
  - "China's Attitude Toward Foreigners," Public Ledger, n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "China's New Aviation Contracts," n.d. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "The Chinese Eastern Railway Problem," n.d. Typescript (Folder 7)
  - "Christianity in China," n.d. Typescript (Folder 8)
  - "The Communists of China," n.d. Typescript and holograph (Folder 9)
  - "Dr. Chen on Chinese Consortium," n.d. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "Dr. Hu Shih," n.d. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - "Dr. Williams Weiching Yen," n.d. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "Dr. Wu Lien-Ten," n.d. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - "Foreign Concessions and Chinese Intrigues," Public Ledger, n.d. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "History of the Central Political Council," n.d. Holograph (Folder 15)
  - "In Memory of Sun Yat-sen," n.d. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - Interview with Baron Tanaka, n.d. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - Interview with Sun Yat-sen, Public Ledger, n.d. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - Interview with Wang Ching-wei, n.d. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "Japan and China at Peace," n.d. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - "Japan, China and Russia," n.d. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - "The Kuomintang," China Year Book, n.d. Printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "Manchukuo of Today," n.d. Typescript (Folder 23)
  - "March of Events," Trans-Pacific, n.d. Seventeen typescript articles (Folder 24)
  - "Memoranda with Regard to the Economic Development of Manchuria," n.d. Two typescript copies (Folder 25)
  - "Memorandum of the Foreign Credit Situation," n.d. Two typescript copies (Folder 26)
  - "Mr. D. Y. Lin," n.d. Typescript (Folder 27)
  - "Mr. T. V. Soong's Budget Plan," n.d. Typescript (Folder 28)
  - "The Nanking Government," n.d. Typescript (Folder 29)
  - "Native Goods in China," n.d. Typescript (Folder 30)
  - Notes on the history of diplomatic service in Shanghai, n.d. Holograph and typescript (Folder 31)
  - "The New Japanese Cabinet," n.d. Typescript (Folder 32)
  - "Opium and Fairplay Again," n.d. Typescript (Folder 33)
  - "Outline of Government," n.d. Holograph (Folder 34)
  - "The Problem of Extraterritoriality," n.d. Typescript (Folder 35)
  - "Rehabilitation: China's First Political Problem," n.d. Typescript (Folder 36)
  - Review of A New Party in Russia, n.d. Typescript (Folder 37)
  - Review of Imperialism and World Politics, n.d. Typescript (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Review of Some Bigger Issues in China's Problems, n.d. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - Review of The Foundations of Modern China, n.d. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - "Roy Anderson - A Character Sketch," n.d. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "The Russians in China," n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "Scheme for the Publication of the Central Journal," n.d. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "Senator Bingham in China," n.d. Typescript (Folder 7)
  - "Shameen Strike Unabated," n.d. Typescript (Folder 8)
  - "Shanghai'ed," n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Sino-Japanese Settlement of the Nanking and Hankow Incidents," n.d. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "A Sound History of the Far East," n.d. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - Speech, n.d. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - Statement by Chiang Ching-tsen, n.d. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - Statement by T. V. Soong, n.d. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Statement of the Shanghai Provisional Court, n.d. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "Strong Man in China," Public Ledger, n.d. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "Taxating (sic) Foreign Goods," n.d. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Taxation in China," n.d. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "Taxing Foreign Goods," n.d. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "Tuchunate in China," Public Ledger, n.d. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - "Wages," n.d. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - "Confidential Report on Conditions in Shanghai," 1920 April 30. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - Article on Mrs. Thomas Lamont, 1920 July 31 (pseudonym used, Georgi Gramada). Typescript (Folder 23)
  - "Memorandum Outlining Present Military-Political Grouping with a Criticism thereon by Sung Hung-yi," 1920 September 1. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - Article on famine, 1920 September 30 (pseudonym used, Georgi Gramada). Typescript (Folder 25)
  - "Memorandum for Mr. B.," 1921 December 1. Typescript (Folder 26)
  - "Foreigners in China," Public Ledger, 1923 March 21. Typescript (Folder 27)
  - "Chinese Politics," Public Ledger, 1923 April 16. Typescript (Folder 28)
  - Article on Chu Chao-hsin, Trans-Pacific, 1923 June 15. Typescript (Folder 29)
  - "Interview with Mr. Wen Shi-tsen," Public Ledger, 1923 July 4. Typescript (Folder 30)
  - Article on Jews in Shanghai, Jewish Telegraph Bureau, 1923 June 8. Typescript (Folder 31)
  - Article on Jews in China, Jewish Press Bureau, 1923 July 19. Typescript (Folder 32)
  - Article on Japanese boycott, Trans-Pacific, 1923 July 20. Typescript (Folder 33)
  - Article on the Lincheng Affair, 1923 July 20. Typescript (Folder 34)
  - "The Diary of a Fortnight," North-China Herald, 1923 September 22. Photostat of printed copy (Folder 35)
  - Article on Chinese characters, Public Ledger, 1924 January 31. Typescript (Folder 36)
  - Article on movies in China, Public Ledger, 1924 February 5. Typescript (Folder 37)
  - Article on Tsao Kun, Public Ledger, 1924 February 10. Typescript (Folder 38)
  - Article on tourists, Public Ledger, 1924 March 11. Typescript (Folder 39)
  - Article on Lenin memorial services, Public Ledger, 1924 March 21. Typescript (Folder 40)
  - Article on antiforeign agitations, Public Ledger, 1924 May 6. Typescript (Folder 41)
  - Article on trade mark law, Public Ledger, 1924 May 6. Typescript (Folder 42)
  - Article on wool exports, 1924 June 9. Typescript (Folder 43)
  - Article on Chinese Emigration, Public Ledger, 1924 June 20. Typescript (Folder 44)
  - "March of Events," 1924 September. Typescript fragment (Folder 45)
  - "Memorandum on Local Political Situation," 1924 November 12. Typescript (Folder 46)
  - Memoranda, 1924 November 18. Two typescript copies (Folder 47)
  - "The Local Political Situation on January 31, 1925," 1925 January 31. Typescript (Folder 48)
  - "March of Events," Trans-Pacific, 1925 February 8. Typescript (Folder 49)
  - "March of Events," Trans-Pacific, 1925 February 9. Typescript (Folder 50)
  - "Wheat and Flour," 1925 February 17. Typescript (Folder 51)
  - "March of Events," Trans-Pacific, 1925 February 21. Three typescript articles (Folder 52)
  - "March of Events," Trans-Pacific, 1925 March 5. Typescript (Folder 53)
  - Obituary for Roy Scott Andersen, North-China Daily News, 12 March 1925. Printed copy (Folder 54)
  - Article on labor movement in China, Japan Advertiser, 1925 July 23. Typescript (Folder 55)
  - "Memorandum on the Current Situation," 1926 October 19. (Folder 56)
  - Typescript
  - Memorandum, 1927 January 1. Typescript (Folder 57)
  - "China in 1927," North-China Daily News, 1927 February 2. (Folder 58)
    Printed copy and proofs
  - "Memorandum on the Nationalist Movement for President Manuel Quezon," 1927 August 5. Typescript (Folder 59)
  - Notes on the Chinese economy, 1928. Holograph (Folder 60)
  - "China Merchants S. N. Co. Under Government Control," North-China Daily News, 1928 March 13. Proofs (Folder 61)
  - "The Russians Leave China," 1928 April. Correspondence and typescript article (Folder 62)
  - "Educator Predicts Massacre in China," Philadelphia Inquirer, 1928 April 13. Typescript (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - "The Jews in China," Menorah Journal, 1928 July 10. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - Article on disbandment in China, 1928 August. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - Article on Young Communist League, 1928 September. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - Article on Hseuh Tu-pu, 1928 October. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - Article on Max Bauer, 1928 October. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - Article on Naking government, 1928 October. Incomplete typescript (Folder 7)
  - "Boycotts and Politics," 1928 October. Typescript (Folder 8)
  - "The Budget System for China," 1928 October. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "More on the Budget System," 1928 October. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - Article on strikes in China, 1928 October 5. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - Statement by Li Ming, 1928 October 6. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - article and holograph notes
  - "The American Presidential Canvass," 1928 November 1. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - Article on Herbert Hoover, 1928 November 8. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Article on political situation in China, 1928 November 16. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - Article on the Central Bank of China, 1928 November 20. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "The Enthronement of the Japanese Emperor," 1928 November 22. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - Article on Disbandment Conference, 1928 December. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - Article on opium, 1928 December. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "The Consortium's Attitude toward China," 1928 December. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - Review of Modern Manchuria and the South Manchuria Railway, 1928 December. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - "Sino-Japanese Amity," Far Eastern Review, 1928 December. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - Article on Albert Thomas, 1928 December 7. Typescript (Folder 23)
  - Review of The Problems of the Pacific, 1928 December 8. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - Article on the Shanghai mint, 1928 December 10. Typescript (Folder 25)
  - Article on Shanghai tramway strike, 1928 December 19. Typescript (Folder 26)
  - Article on Wang Chung-hui, 1928 December 21. Typescript (Folder 27)
  - Article on the Chinese Communist Party, 1928 December 22. Typescript (Folder 28)
  - Review of Factory Workers in Tangku, 1929 January. Typescript (Folder 29)
  - "Third Party Congress and its Work," North China Daily News, 1929 April 5. Proofs (Folder 30)
  - "The Japanese Evacuation of Shantung," 1929 May 15. Typescript (Folder 31)
  - "The Failure of the Mexican Revolution," 1929 May 28. Typescript (Folder 32)
  - Article on Shanghai Telephone Co., 1929 May 29. Typescript (Folder 33)
  - "Some Railway Problems in China," 1929 June 20. Typescript (Folder 34)
  - "Report on Progress in Manchuria, 1907-1928," 1929 June 24. Typescript (Folder 35)
  - Article on Wilbur Burton, 1929 June 27. Typescript (Folder 36)
  - Article on Chinese judicial system, 1929 July 9. Typescript (Folder 37)
  - "China's Loan Prospects," 1929 July 16. Typescript (Folder 38)
  - "The Story of the Chinese Eastern Railway," North-China Daily News, 1929 July 22 - September 11. Eight typescript articles (incomplete series) and correspondence (Folder 39)
  - Article on Chinese monetary policy, 1929 July 25. Typescript (Folder 40)
  - Article on Chinese Nationalist government loans, 1929 September 25. Typescript (Folder 41)
  - Review of The Development of China, 1929 September 25. Typescript (Folder 42)
  - Article on Japanese politics, 1929 October 1. Typescript (Folder 43)
  - Article on Wellington Koo, 1929 October 4. Typescript (Folder 44)
  - Speech on extraterritoriality in China, University of Chicago, 1930 June. Typescript (Folder 45)
  - "Soviet Influence in China," 1930 August 2. Speech given at the Conference on Russian Affairs of the Institute of Politics, Williamstown. Typescript (Folder 46)
  - Speech on the Far East, 1930 August 25. Typescript copy and draft (Folder 47)
  - "Memorandum for his Excellency, Dr. H. H. Kung," 1930 December 11. Typescript (Folder 48)
  - Article on C. J. Soong, 1932(?). Two typescript drafts (Folder 49)
  - The Tinder Box of Asia, 1932. Typescript draft (fragment) (Folder 50)
  - We Jews, 1934. Correspondence (Folder 51)
  - The Automobile Industry, 1935 (Box 129)
    - Draft and notes. Holograph and typescript (Folder 1)
    - Research material. Printed matter and correspondence (Folder 2)
  - "The Soongs of China," The Atlantic, 1936 December 29. Typescript and correspondence (Folder 3)
  - "The American Way of Life," a series published in Liberty 1938
    - Research material. Articles, brochures, pamphlets, and typescript notes (Folder 4-6)
    - Research material (Box 130, Folder 1-4)
    - Research material (Contd.) (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Holograph notes, typescript drafts, proofs, and printed articles (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - 1938 January - July (Folder 3)
      - 1938 August - 1939 March (Folder 4)
  - Speech at Liberty dinner, 1938. Typescript (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - "Boys Will Be Men: The Buchanan Way," This Week, 1938 February. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 2)
  - "Unbeatable," unpublished article for This Week, 1938 July 7. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 3)
  - "Master Builders," unpublished article for This Week, 1938 July 19. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 4)
  - "The Children's Theater," 1939 July 25. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 5)
  - "Republican Prospects," The American Mercury, 1939 November 7. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 6)
  - Debates with Upton Sinclair and Norman Thomas, 1940. Correspondence, printed matter, and typescript preparatory material (Folder 7)
  - "A Bird in the Hand," unpublished story, 1941(?). Correspondence and typescript (Folder 8)
  - Lectures, 1942. Clippings, correspondence, itineraries, and programs (Folder 9)
  - Lectures, 1943. Clippings, correspondence, itineraries (Folder 10)
  - and programs
  - Address on "America's Town Meeting of the Air," 1943 March 2. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - Debate with Earl Browder, 1943 March 21. Correspondence and flier (Folder 12)
  - Memoranda on various political topics, 1943 June 2 - November 18. Eight typescript texts (Folder 13)
  - Lectures, 1944. Correspondence and itineraries (Folder 14)
  - Memorandum on the international situation, 1944 February 14. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - Debate with Earl Browder on "Wake Up, America!" 1944 October 8 (cancelled). Correspondence and typescript preparatory material (Folder 16)
  - Memorandum on the 1944 election, 1944 November 28. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - Lectures, 1945. Clippings, correspondence, and programs (Folder 18)
  - Memorandum on New York City mayoralty election, 1945 June 19. Typescript (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - "The Republican Party," unpublished article for Encyclopedia Americana, 1945 October. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 2)
  - Lectures, 1946. Correspondence (Folder 3)
  - "The Tone of the Day," Call Board, 1946 April 23. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 4)
  - "The Clash of Civilizations," commencement address at the University of Notre Dame, 1946 June 30
    - Correspondence and itinerary (Folder 5)
    - Press releases, typescript, and printed copies (Folder 6)
  - "Land of Opportunity," article for King Features Syndicate, 1946 September (Folder 7)
  - Debate with Earl Browder, "American Forum of the Air," 1946 September 24. Typescript preparatory material (Folder 8)
  - Lectures, 1947. Correspondence and itineraries (Folder 9)
  - "The Bolshevik Revolution," address, the American Legion, Washington, D. C., 1947 November 17. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - Lectures, 1948. Clippings and correspondence (Folder 11)
  - "Dignity and Liberty," commencement address at the Montana School of Mines, 1948 May 28. Article and correspondence (Folder 12)
  - Lectures, 1949. Correspondence (Folder 13)
  - Lectures, 1950. Clippings and correspondence (Folder 14)
  - "The Source of Human Rights," address at the University of Notre Dame, 1950 December 8. Clipping, correspondence, itinerary, and program (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Lectures, 1951. Clippings, correspondence, and itineraries
      - January - June (Folder 2)
      - July - December (Folder 3)
  - Lecture on the Bill of Rights, 1951 September 25. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - Panel discussion on natural law, University of Notre Dame, 1951 December 14-15. Correspondence, itinerary, and program (Folder 5)
  - Lectures, 1952-1957. Clippings, correspondence, itineraries, and programs
    - 1952 (Folder 6)
    - 1953 (Folder 7)
    - 1954 (Box 135)
      - January - June (Folder 1)
      - July - December (Folder 2)
    - 1955 (Folder 3)
    - 1956 (Folder 4)
    - 1957 (Folder 5)
  - "Russia in the News," unpublished article for Dateline, 1957 May. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 6)
  - Lectures, 1958. Clippings, correspondence, itineraries, and programs (Folder 7)
  - "An Urgent Plea for Anglo-American Union," Freedom and Union, 1958 November. Printed copy and photostats (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Lectures, 1959-1961. Clippings, correspondence, itineraries, and programs
    - 1959 (Folder 2)
    - 1960 - 1961 (Folder 3)
  - "The U.N. and the U.S.," Saturday Review, 1962 February 24. Printed copy (Folder 4)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS WRITTEN FOR OTHERS, 1938-1962
  - Baruch, Bernard M., 1958 November 7. Typescript (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Berlin, Richard E., 1947 October 20 - 1960 October 14. Six typescript drafts and one printed copy (Folder 6)
  - Bond, Ward, 1960 February 21. Typescript (Folder 7)
  - Bricker, John W., 1943 September - November 26. Two typescript drafts (Folder 8)
  - Chiang, May-ling Soong, 1948 January 1 - 1959 February 21. Correspondence, telegram, and ten typescript drafts (Folder 9)
  - Chiang, Kai-shek, 1949 May 26. Typescript (Folder 10)